Taylor Wilkinson

DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

PORTFOLIO EMAIL GITHUB taylorwilkinson.ca tjwilkinsonn@gmail.com qithub.com/TaylorWilkinson

"HELLO, WORLD!"

I'm a front-end web developer with a strong interest in user-experience design. I love to build applications and solve problems, appreciating any chance to express my creativity and challenge myself. As an articulate communicator, I'm able to engage with teammates and clients alike to achieve the most desired result. I'm your friendly, neighbourhood Myers-Briggs INFP.

SKILLS

CODE **DESIGN & MEDIA SOFTWARE HTML** Adobe Creative Suite Web Design CSS Wireframing Adobe Experience Manager **JavaScript** Graphic Design AxureRP PHP Game Design **XAMPP** Photography Java Unity C#

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT STUDENT

BlackBerry (May 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Developed a form validator for components on BlackBerry's authoring site
- Built, edited, and migrated web pages, improving SEO and lead generation for the sales department
- Liasied with internal clients when building pages, providing input on design and layout

COMMUNICATIONS ASSISTANT CO-OP

Adoptive Families Association of BC (Sep - Dec 2017)

- Conceptualized a social media video campaign for Adoption Awareness Month with the goal of normalizing adoption
- Organized the "Light Up for Adoption Awareness" event, which involved recruiting participants and writing a press release in collaboration with BC's Ministry of Children and Family Development
- Designed visual content (including infographics, posters, e-mail banners, and holiday cards) for social media, internal clients, AFABC events, and AFABC's magazine, Focus On Adoption

FINANCIAL SERVICE ASSOCIATE

Prospera Credit Union (Feb 2016-Apr 2018, Sep 2018-Apr 2019)

- Identified financial needs of the members through effective communication and building rapport
- Assisted other staff by preparing documents, conducting promotional and appointment phone calls, and referring members for sales opportunities
- Created in-branch marketing materials (i.e. posters and sandwich board signs) to promote specials and events to members and staff

PROJECTS

BLACKBERRY FORM VALIDATOR

Web Developer (Aug 2018)

- Asked to develop a form validator for BlackBerry's authoring site when I requested additional work during my co-op placement at BlackBerry
- Familiarized myself with JavaScript, regular expressions (RegEx), and researched Adobe Experience Manager documentation and similar approaches to form validation
- Practiced iterative development and gained further experience in JavaScript development, debugging and finding solutions for issues in large-scale code environments that I am seeing for the first time

SPROUT CREDIT UNION

Web Developer (Mar 2018)

- Designed and built a website for a fictional company with an emphasis on responsive design. for a month-long project in a team of two.
- Built using HTML5 and CSS3
- Wrote the copy for the majority of the webpages
- Gained an improved understanding of effective information design and web design

TIME'S PAST

Lead Game Developer (Dec 2018)

- Built a Untiy narrative puzzle game as part of a two person team
- Wrote scripts in C# and JavaScript, and researched open source libraries for handling lighting and cutscenes
- Collaborated with my Creative Lead to implement her animations and other art assets, and also assisted with level design
- Placed 2nd overall in our class showcase, judged by teaching staff and local Vancouver game industry professionals

EDUCATION

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY School of Interactive Arts and Technology Sept 2014 - Present

UNIVERSITY OF VICTORIA Department of Biochemistry Sept 2012 - Apr 2013

INTERESTS



VIDEOGAMES

My favorite games to play includes Stardew Valley, Overwatch, Spyro the Dragon, and Pokémon.



SWIMMING

My favorite stroke is butterfly, partially because no one else would want to do it in relays and I'm a sucker for punishment.



DUNGEONS & DRAGONS

Playing D&D with friends isn't just fun, but is also a creative outlet where we can improvise to create a compelling narrative.